RG 170:001, Mansfield Training School
Connecticut State Library
- Series 5. Civil Defense, 1943-1955
  - Connecticut civil defense organization oath, circa 1950 (Box 35, Folder 47)
  - Facts about the H bomb that could save your life / Federal Civil Defense Administration, 1955 (Box 35, Folder 48)
  - Survival under atomic attack; the official U. S. Government booklet, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 49-52)
    Multiple copies, each with a name inscribed on the front cover.
- Series 6. Residents, 1884-1986
  - Admission and discharge records, 1884-1986
    - Parole and discharge book, 1944 December 24-1963 June 30; 1 volume (Box Item 37)
    - Discharge book, 1963 July 1-1986 June 30; 1 volume (Box Item 38)
    - Transfer/parole diaries
      - 1944 October 1-1958 December 31, 12 volumes (Box 39)
      - 1959-1964, 6 volumes (Box 40)
    - Roll call books
      - Section A, 1966 September-1973 June; 4 volumes (Box 63)
      - Section B, 1963 July-1974 March; 6 volumes (Box 63)
      - Section C, 1963 December-1965 February; 1 volume (Box 63)
      - Section D, 1969 March-1973 August; 2 volumes (Box 63)
    - Birth certificate forms and receipts, 1917-1940 (Box 66A, Folder 1)
    - *CLUSTR manual, 1983 August-1984 February (Box 66A, Folder 2-7)
    - Death certificate stubs, 1917 December 2-1944 April 22 (Box 66A, Folder 8-19)
    - Orders of commitment from Probate Court to Mansfield Training School, 1917-1919 (Box 66A, Folder 20)
    - Transit Permits, 1927 December 24-1944 July 14 (Box 66A, Folder 21-25)
    - Admission index cards (Box 132)
      - Female, A-Mai, 1884-1961 (Box 132)
      - Female, Mal-Z, 1884-1961 (Box 133)
      - Male, A-Carl, circa 1884-1961
      - Male, Car-Pau, circa 1884-1961 (Box 134)
      - Male, Pav-Z, circa 1884-1961 (Box 135)
    - Discharge/Transfer/Death index cards (Box 135)
      - Female, A-Hoa, 1918-1948 (Box 135)
      - Female, Hol-Z, 1918-1948 (Box 136)
      - Female, A-Z, 1947-1952 (Box 136)
      - Male, A-Z, 1947-1952 (Box 136)
    - Registration cards, circa 1920-1939 (Box 137)
    - Resident admission index cards, 1933-1949 (Box 138)
    - Case records of discharged residents, 1920-1959; 1992-055
      Compiled by the Social Services Department.
      - Acato-Bakula (Box 1)
      - Balfour-Bingham (Box 2)
      - Birmingam-Brown, E. (Box 3)
      - Brown, F.-Carp (Box 4)
      - Carpenter-Coppola (Box 5)
      - Corbett-DiMauriac (Box 6)
      - Dini-Foster (Box 7)
      - Fowler-Gionfriddo (Box 8)
      - Glass-Guy (Box 9)
      - Hadden-Hine (Box 10)
      - Hitchcock-Jewett (Box 11)
      - Jodoin-King, N. (Box 12)
      - King, R.-Lankton (Box 13)
      - LaPlante-Malicki (Box 14)
      - Malnyk-Montagno (Box 15)
      - Montgomery-Natuenwicz (Box 16)
      - Nejelski-Payne, Ea. (Box 17)
      - Payne, Ev.-Rand (Box 18)
      - Ranney-Sands, R. (Box 19)
      - Sands, W.-Smythe (Box 20)
      - Snedeker-Strigess (Box 21)
      - Succio-Tucker (Box 22)
      - Turner-Wilson (Box 23)
      - Wing-Zysek (Box 24)
  - Medical records, 1941-1981
    - Doctor books
      - 1956-1968 May 30, 20 volumes (Box 41)
      - 1968 June 1-1976 April 23, 13 volumes (Box 42)
      - 1970 January 17-1979 July 6, 12 volumes (Box 43)
    - Daily logs
      - 1941, 14 volumes (Box 44)
      - 1941-1957, 11 volumes (Box 45)
      - 1958-1960, 13 volumes (Box 46)
      - 1961-1962, 11 volumes (Box 47)
      - 1963-1965, 15 volumes (Box 48)
      - 1966-1968, 14 volumes (Box 49)
      - 1969-1970, 13 volumes (Box 50)
      - 1971-1973, 16 volumes (Box 51)
      - 1974-1976, 11 volumes (Box 52)
      - 1977-1979, 18 volumes (Box 53)
      - 1978-1981, 16 volumes (Box 54)
    - Female/male clinic books, 1975-1978, 1980; 7 volumes (Box 55)
    - Resident files
      - A-Calh, circa 1956-1981 (Box 56)
      - Call-Fac, circa 1956-1981 (Box 57)
      - Far-Hoe, circa 1956-1981 (Box 58)
      - Hof-Mil, circa 1956-1981 (Box 59)
      - Mim-Row, circa 1956-1981 (Box 60)
      - Row-Wal, circa 1956-1981 (Box 61)
      - Wan-Z, circa 1956-1981 (Box 62)
    - Anecdotal records, 1981 February-August (Box 62)
    - Diabetic charts, 1969-1974 (Box 62)
    - Forced fluids daily charts, 1970 January-March (Box 62)
    - Height and weight charts, 1962-1969 (Box 62)
    - Seizure charts, 1966-1970 (Box 62)
    - Patient attending clinic forms (Box 62)
      - Section A, 1970 December 1-1971 May 28 (Box 62)
      - Section D, 1969 March-1973 June (Box 62)
      - 1969 March 3-1971 September 30 (Box 62)
    - Bowel movement books
      - Section A, 1969 September-1971 March; 1 volume (Box 63)
      - Section B, 1965 February-1973 March; 3 volumes (Box 63)
      - Section C, 1963 January-1964 March; 1 volume (Box 63)
      - Section D, 1972 January-1973 August; 1 volume (Box 63)
    - Catamenial records (Box 63)
      - Section A, 1966 July-1970 January; 1 volume (Box 63)
      - Section B, 1962 December-1973 August; 3 volumes (Box 63)
      - Section C, 1964 October-1971 July; 1 volume (Box 63)
      - Section C, 1963-1970 (Box 62)
      - Section D, 1963-1972 (Box 62)
      - Merritt, 1965-1971 (Box 62)
      - 1965-1976 (Box 62)
      - 1971-1974 March (Box 63)
    - Height and weight books (Box 63)
      - Section A, 1969 January-1970 January; 1 volume (Box 63)
      - Section B, 1969 April-1973 September; 1 volume (Box 63)
      - Section D, 1965 June-1969 April; 1 volume (Box 63)
    - Temperature books (Box 63)
      - Section A, 1970 February 4-1971 December 31; 2 volumes (Box 63)
      - Section B, 1970 December 6-1974 March 8; 2 volumes (Box 63)
      - Section C, 1970 February 4-1971 May 12; 1 volume (Box 63)
    - Dental records
      - Females, 1944-1949 (Box 64, Folder 1-19)
      - Males, 1944-1949 (Box 64, Folder 20-36)
      - Females and males, 1950-1951 (Box 64, Folder 37)
      - Blank examination forms, undated (Box 64, Folder 38)
      - Notes, 1949 (Box 64, Folder 39)
      - List of patients, 1949 May-1950 March (Box 64, Folder 40)
      - X-rays, 1947-1950 (Box 137)
    - Outpatient files, circa 1929-1959
      - M-S (Box 66A, Folder 26-33)
  - Residential life, circa 1944-1982
    - 1. Absentee from Hospital or Institution Form; 2. Request for Change in Resident's Building; 3. Resident Lists, 1969 August 21; undated (Box 64, Folder 41)
    - Activities, 1981 March (Box 64, Folder 42)
    - Activities of daily living and bathing check list, 1981 March (Box 64, Folder 43)
    - Activity logs, 1981 March-1982 March (Box 64, Folder 44)
    - The Catholic Hymnal Volume 1, 1968 (Box 64, Folder 45)
    - The Catholic Hymnal Volume 2 for Christmas, Lent Easter, 1968 (Box 64, Folder 46)
    - Classification forms, undated (Box 64, Folder 47)
    - Clothing inventories (Box 64)
      - A-K, circa 1944-1973 (Box 64, Folder 48-59)
      - L-Z, circa 1944-1973 (Box 65, Folder 1-15)
    - Dining skills observation forms, undated (Box 65, Folder 16)
    - Packages received list, 1967-1971 (Box 65, Folder 17)
    - The Press, 1946 August-1950 July (Box 65, Folder 18-21)
    - Recreation center menu, 1981 July 1 (Box 65, Folder 22)
    - Recreational, religious and social activities, 1946-1947, 1950, 1967 (Box 65, Folder 23)
    - Residents' background and behavioral difficulties, circa 1945 (Box 65, Folder 24)
    - Residents' background information, 1973 January (Box 65, Folder 25)
    - Residents' family contact information, undated (Box 65, Folder 26-27)
    - Residents' placements, 1970 March 1 (Box 65, Folder 28)
    - Visitor slips (Box 65)
      - Female residents, A-L (Box 65, Folder 29-41)
      - Female residents, M-W, 1957-1964 (Box 66, Folder 1-9)
      - Male residents, A-Malb, 1957-64 (Box 66, Folder 10-26)
      - Male residents, Malt-Z, 1957-64 (Box 66A, Folder 34-44)
    - Visiting information, 1963 June 7, undated (Box 66A, Folder 45-48)
- Series 7. Personnel, 1912-1989
  Box 69A is RESTRICTED.
  Boxes 67-69, and 139-143 are UNRESTRICTED.
  - Employment agreements, R-Z, 1931-1943 (Box 67, Folder 1-4)
  - Employees' departure/transfer records binder 1, 1916-1918 (Box 67, Folder 5-15)
  - Employees' departure/transfer records binder 2, 1918-1922 (Box 67, Folder 16-30)
  - Employees' departure/transfer records binder 3, 1923-1926 (Box 67, Folder 31-42)
  - Employees' departure/transfer records binder 4, 1926-1933 (Box 67, Folder 43-53)
  - Employee time cards, 1980 (Box 67, Folder 54)
  - Residential care department supervisors' meeting, 1969 September 24 (Box 67, Folder 55)
  - Supervisory training workshop, undated (Box 67, Folder 56)
  - Employee notices, 1941-1982 (Box 67, Folder 57-75)
  - Employee notices book, 1941-1947 (Box 67, Folder 76-82)
  - Standard procedures and notices binder, 1941-1952 (Box 68, Folder 1-14)
  - Standard procedures and notices withdrawn from binder, 1948-1949 (Box 68, Folder 15)
  - Standard procedures and notices book, 1941-1946, 1949 (Box 68, Folder 16-18)
  - Cleaners, undated (Box 68, Folder 19)
  - Dining routine, undated (Box 68, Folder 20)
  - Laundry items and equipment, 1964 May 20 (Box 68, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969-1970 (Box 68, Folder 22)
  - Personnel procedures regarding evacuation of Goddard Hall and absenteeism, 1979-1980 (Box 68, Folder 23)
  - Positions, 1942-1956 (Box 68, Folder 24)
  - Psychotropic medication, undated (Box 68, Folder 26)
  - Restraints study teams, 1974 October 7 (Box 68, Folder 25)
  - Routines and responsibilities, 1974 (Box 68, Folder 27)
  - Time schedules covering pay periods, 1969 October 31-1970 December 24 (Box 68, Folder 28-31)
  - The Mansfield Weekly Volumes 1-749, 1966 March 13-1980 October 17 (Box 68, Folder 32-71)
    Issues for 1966-1975 available at
  - Award ceremonies programs, 1971-1980 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - The Mansfielder, 1970-1971 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Mirsky, Arlene C., 1971 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Employee guidebook, 1981 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Employment application, undated (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Music festival fall show program, 1971 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Policies and Guidelines for the Behavior Management of Clients of the Mansfield Training School, 1975 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - The Mansfielder Volume I, Numbers 5-13; Volume II Number 1 - Volume III Number 1, 1972-1975 (Box 69, Folder 8-9)
    A copy is available at and
  - The Mansfielder layout, 1970-1975, undated (Box 69, Folder 10-28)
  - The Mansfielder layout - clippings, 1971-1972 (Box 69, Folder 29)
  - The Mansfielder layout - miscellaneous, circa 1970-1972, undated (Box 69, Folder 30-33)
  - Dismissal and legal action regarding Elly C. Fischer, Florence M. Nicols, James P. Purcell and Dr. Helen T. Warner, 1942-1946 (Box 69, Folder 34-43)
  - Employees' departure/transfer diaries, 1943-1948; 6 volumes (Box 69)
  - Greeting cards - Mirsky, Arlene C., circa 1970, undated (Box 69A, Folder 1)
  - List of employees, 1987-1989 (Box 69A, Folder 2-3)
  - Unit E minutes, 1979 May 24-October 11 (Box 69A, Folder 4-6)
  - Employee information cards, 1912-1941 (Box 139-140)
    May include beneficiary, contact, departure and state service information.
  - Personnel quota index cards
    - 1954-1957 June (Box 141)
    - 1957 June-1960 (Box 142)
    - 1960-1963 (Box 143)
- Series 8. Finances, 1916-1981
  Box 70A is RESTRICTED.
  Boxes 70-73, 75-76, 144, and item 74 are UNRESTRICTED.
  - Addition to payroll slips, 1941-1956 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Drop from payroll slips, 1942-1957 (Box 70, Folder 2-3)
  - Miscellaneous payroll change slips, 1941-1957 (Box 70, Folder 4-11)
  - Requisitions for drugs and medical supplies, 1969, 1973 (Box 70, Folder 12-17)
  - Transfer from payroll slips, A-S, 1941-1956 (Box 70, Folder 18)
  - Dental bill, price list and requisitions, 1950-1951 (Box 70A, Folder 1)
  - Requisitions for drugs and medical supplies, 1980-1982 (Box 70A, Folder 2-7)
  - Residents' accounts receipts, 1963-1965 (Box 70A, Folder 8)
  - Appropriation accounts, 1923-1929 (Box 71)
  - Sales and miscellaneous accounts, 1919-1940 (Box 71)
  - Inventory and business statements, 1919 (Box 71)
  - Bank statements, 1923 December-1924 March (Box 72)
  - New construction accounts, 1916-1918; 1 volume (Box 72)
  - Building accounts, 1921-1923 (Box 72)
  - Cash journal, 1916 October-1918 July; 1 volume (Box 73)
  - Expense journal, 1919 July-September; 1 volume (Box 73)
  - Purchase ledger, 1919-1923; 1 volume (Box Item 74)
  - Cash receipt register & activity fund ledger, 1944-1952; 1 volume (Box 75)
  - Expense ledger, 1954-1958; 1 volume (Box 75)
  - Farm account, 1918 October-1920 June; 1 volume (Box 75)
  - Farm reports, 1953 July-1955 June; 1 volume (Box 75)
  - Farm reports, 1958 July-1961 April; 1 volume (Box 75)
  - Gas and oil reports, 1957 March-1958 June; 1 volume (Box 75)
  - Gas and oil reports, 1959 May-1960 January; 1 volume (Box 75)
  - General ledger, 1919-1923; 1 volume (Box 75)
  - Meal data, 1953-1961; 1 volume (Box 75)
  - Pay roll sheets, 1917 June-1918 June; 1918 July-1919 June; 1 volume (Box 76)
  - Pay roll sheets, 1917 July-1918 June; 1919 July-1921 June; 1 volume (Box 76)
  - Pay roll check book, 1928 April 28; 1 volume (Box 76)
  - Expenses for equipment index cards, 1942-1949 (Box 144)
- Series 9. Reports, 1917-1990
  Boxes 77-87, and items 99-102 are RESTRICTED.
  Boxes 76A, and 88-98 are UNRESTRICTED.
  - Annual reports, 1955-1990 (Box 76A, Folder 1-16)
    A copy is available at and and
  - Auditors' report for fiscal years ended June 30…, 1974-1976, 1988 (Box 76A, Folder 17-19)
  - Capacity and population reports, 1960 September-1964 November (Box 76A, Folder 20-25)
  - Digest of departmental reports, 1965-1966 (Box 76A, Folder 26)
  - Final Report of the Mansfield Training School Task Force to Governor William A. O'Neil, 1990 April; photocopy (Box 76A, Folder 27)
  - Governor's digest, 1967-1971 (Box 76A, Folder 28-29)
  - Items discarded, 1958 (Box 76A, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1976-1987, undated (Box 76A, Folder 31)
  - Program assessment, 1971 December (Box 76A, Folder 32)
  - Progress reports (Box 76A)
    - Hospital improvement program, 1969 (Box 76A, Folder 33)
    - 1. John F. Kennedy "Flames of Hope Inc., Candle Project" 2. Mansfield social adjustment project, 1969 (Box 76A, Folder 34)
  - Proof of population reports, 1955-1962 (Box 76A, Folder 35-41)
  - Report on Site Visit to Mansfield Training School, 1980-1982 (Box 76A, Folder 42)
  - Respite Care Provided by the Department of Mental Retardation by Cote, Terry, Program Development Coordinator, Connecticut Department of Mental Retardation, 1987 February (Box 76A, Folder 43)
  - Tables to unidentified reports, 1956 July-1964 October (Box 76A, Folder 44-47)
  - Accountability sheets, 1980 December 8-1982 February 19 (Box 77, Folder 1-4)
  - Census, 1927-1961 (Box 77, Folder 5-44)
  - Census data, 1963-1964 January (Box 78, Folder 1-12)
  - Commissioner's reports
    - 1955 January-1961 March (Box 79, Folder 1-63)
    - 1961 April-December (Box 80, Folder 1-9)
  - Connecticut study of known retarded persons (Box 80)
    - Purpose and instructions, 1958 May 19 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Mental defectives and epileptics females (Box 80)
      - Baker Hall, 1958 (Box 80, Folder 11-18)
      - Binet Hall, 1958 (Box 80, Folder 19-25)
      - Goddard Hall, 1958 (Box 80, Folder 26-31)
      - Hospital Ward III, 1958 (Box 80, Folder 32-33)
      - Hospital Ward IV, 1958 (Box 80, Folder 34-35)
      - La Moure Hall, 1958 (Box 80, Folder 36-40)
      - Matthews Hall, 1958 (Box 80, Folder 41-49)
      - Merritt Hall, 1958 (Box 80, Folder 50-60)
      - Thomson Hall A-C, 1958 (Box 80, Folder 61-68)
      - Thomson Hall D-Z, 1958 (Box 81, Folder 1-2)
      - Tregold Hall, 1958 (Box 81, Folder 3-9)
      - Wallace Hall, 1958 (Box 81, Folder 10-19)
    - Mental defectives and epileptics males (Box 81)
      - Campbell Hall, 1958 (Box 81, Folder 20-32)
      - Fernald Hall, 1958 (Box 81, Folder 33-43)
      - Hospital Ward I, 1958 (Box 81, Folder 44-45)
      - Hospital Ward II, 1958 (Box 81, Folder 46-47)
      - Johnstone Hall, 1958 (Box 81, Folder 48-57)
      - Marvin Hall A-R, 1958 (Box 81, Folder 58-65)
      - Marvin Hal S-Z, 1958 (Box 82, Folder 1-5)
      - Rogers Hall, 1958 (Box 82, Folder 6-16)
      - Seguin Hall, 1958 (Box 82, Folder 17-25)
      - Storrs Hall, 1958 (Box 82, Folder 26-32)
      - Thomson Hall, 1958 (Box 82, Folder 33-37)
  - Consolidated census reports (Box 82)
    - 1958 January-1960 April (Box 82, Folder 38-65)
    - 1960 May-1961 December (Box 83, Folder 1-20)
  - Dentist's daily reports, 1949 July-1951 February (Box 83, Folder 21-34)
  - Draft data, 1952, 1957 (Box 83, Folder 35)
  - Lists and classifications, 1937-1951 (Box 83, Folder 36)
  - Monthly population reports, 1948 July-1964 October (Box 83, Folder 37-53)
  - Monthly population report transmittal letters, 1948-1949 (Box 83, Folder 54)
  - Movement of patient population reports, 1955 July-1964 October (Box 83, Folder 55-59)
  - Officer of the day reports, 1969 September 5 (Box 83, Folder 60)
  - Master restraint sheets, undated (Box 83, Folder 61)
  - Therapeutic restraint and seclusion reports
    - 1963 December 1-1964 May 9 (Box 84, Folder 1-27)
    - 1964 May 10-October 31 (Box 85, Folder 1-30)
    - 1964 November 1-1965 June 5 (Box 86, Folder 1-38)
    - 1965 June 6-October 31, 1974 (Box 87, Folder 1-27)
  - Boys' and girls' dormitories resident and staff information, 1926-1927 (Box 87, Folder 28)
  - Operative and medical data binder, 1944-1945 (Box 87, Folder 29-33)
  - Daily reports
    - 1962 December 30-1963 January 18 (Box 88)
    - 1963 January 19-February 5 (Box 89)
    - 1963 February 7-24 (Box 90)
    - 1963 February 25-March 15 (Box 91)
    - 1963 March 16-31 (Box 92)
    - 1963 May 1-18 (Box 93)
    - 1963 May 19-May 31 (Box 94)
    - 1963 June 14-30 (Box 95)
    - 1965 January 21-February 10 (Box 96)
    - 1965 February 11-28 (Box 97)
    - 1965 March 1-8 (Box 98)
  - Monthly attendance reports
    - 1917 July-1918 October, 1 volume (Box Item 99)
    - 1917 August-1933 December, 1 volume (Box Item 100)
    - 1934 January-1951 June, 1 volume (Box Item 101)
    - 1941 July-1961 February, 1 volume (Box Item 102)
- Series 10. Facilities, 1888-1992
  - Transmittal letters with enclosed deeds and other related real estate documents, 1888-1927, 1959 (Box 103, Folder 1-6)
  - Real estate deeds, 1906-1926 (Box 103, Folder 7-11)
  - Real estate deeds and notes on real estate, 1927, undated (Box 103, Folder 12)
  - Central Vermont Railroad agreements, leases and payments, 1931, 1983-1991 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Connecticut Department of Correction's use and occupancy agreement, 1988 June 14 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Connecticut State Museum of Natural History use of Mansfield Training School, 1988-1989 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Hockanum Industries greenhouse and woodlot leases, 1978-1988 (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - University of Connecticut farm, 1968-1975 (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - University of Connecticut farm, 1981-1988 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Land information, 1968-1978 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - 1. Letter regarding well 2. Description of base line points, 1945, undated (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Map of grounds, undated (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Building closings, 1987-1991 (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - Building closings and savings, 1987-1989 (Box 104, Folder 11)
  - Building information, 1975-1992 (Box 104, Folder 12-16)
  - Day care center, 1987-1990 (Box 105, Folder 1a-3)
  - Building inventory assessments, 1962-1965 (Box 105, Folder 4-6)
  - Equipment inventories, 1962-1964, 1974 (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - Work order procedures, 1980-1981 (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - National registry of historic places, 1985-1988 (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - Mansfield Training School National Register of Historic Places certificate, 1987 December 22 (Box 105, Folder 10)
  - Dairy building specifications, undated (Box 105, Folder 11)
  - Proposals and bond for construction and equipment, 1930 April - 1931 September (Box 105, Folder 12)
  - Proposals for construction and equipment, 1932 July 12 (Box 105, Folder 13-14)
  - Proposed land agreements, 1931, 1990 (Box 105, Folder 15)
  - Recommendations for open spaces/recreational uses, 1989 November 9 (Box 105, Folder 16)
  - Towner and Sellew's school plans brochures, circa 1927 (Box 105, Folder 17)
  - Conversion of nurses home to building for industrial department; Converting one family into three apartments, 1942 September 4; blueprint, 4 sheets (Box Map case)
  - Kitchen renovations for Merritt Hall, 1990 May 18; blueprint, 6 sheets (Box Map case)
  - Right of way map, 1932 October 31; 4 sheet + 1 letter (Box Map case)
  - Topographical map, 1950 October; 1 sheet (Box Map case)
  - Safety renovations Knight Hospital building, 1973 October 4; blueprint, 15 sheets (Box Map case)
  - Safety renovations Knight Hospital building, 1973 December 5; blueprint, 21 sheets (Box Map case)
  - Blueprint. Remodel Knight Hospital Complex project, 1980 June 9; blueprint, 13 sheets (Box Map case)
- Series 11. Photographs and slides, circa 1927-1991
  - Photographs and slides (Box 106-116)
    Detail listing available at History and Genealogy reference desk.
  - Photographs (Box 145-146)
    No listing available.
- Series 12. Scrapbooks, 1946-1956
  - Scrapbook, 1946-1948, 1953-1956; 1 volume (Box Item 117)
    Includes newspaper articles about the mentally challenged in general as well as specifics to Connecticut, Southbury and Mansfield Training School.
  - Scrapbook, 1946-1955; 1 volume (Box Item 118)
    Focuses on newspaper articles relating to Mansfield Training School.
  - Poster boards for event/exhibit, 15 items (Box Map case)
- Series 13. Artifacts, circa 1949-1975, undated
  Box 120 is RESTRICTED.
  Box 119 is UNRESTRICTED.
  - Canteen ticket book, 1975 (Box 119)
  - Wooden ship plaque, calendar and bracket, circa 1949 (Box 119)
  - Mansfield Training School 20 year service pin (Box 119)
  - Mansfield Training School Foundation corporate seal (Box 119)
  - Mansfield Training School Nursing Services patches, 2 patches (Box 119)
  - Gideon's Bible (Box 119)
  - Resident's comment, 1 page (Box 120)
    Recorded in "National Diary for 1962".
  - "Activity Program for Merritt Hall Day by Day Record of Who Participates and What is Done.", 1966 January 10-25 (Box 120)
    Recorded in "National Diary for 1964".
- Series 14. Training, circa 1968-1984, undated
  Boxes 121-125, 130-131, and items 126-129 are RESTRICTED due to condition.
  Boxes 120A is UNRESTRICTED.
  - Employee's Basic Guide for Fire Prevention and Safety, 1972 (Box 120A, Folder 1)
  - Inservice training manual, 1968 (Box 120A, Folder 2)
    UNRESTRICTED
  - Proposed outline guide for inservice training, 1975 (Box 120A, Folder 3)
  - Training for Research and Service in the field of Mental Retardation, Bulletin on, 1966-1967 (Box 120A, Folder 4)
  - Training guides, undated (Box 120A, Folder 5)
  - Basic standards for the residential services of the Mansfield Training School manual, undated (Box 120A, Folder 6-7)
  - Basic standards for the residential services daily schedule, 1982 May (Box 120A, Folder 8)
  - Mansfield Training School health care manual, 1982 (Box 120A, Folder 9)
  - Water safety regulations, 1974, 1979, 1980 (Box 120A, Folder 10-12)
  - Use of manual language dictionary, undated (Box 120A, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified film (Box 121)
  - The digestive system of the human body", film strip (Box 122)
  - Gerontology, audio cassette (Box 122)
  - Mansfield Training School orientation, 1977 April; audio cassette (Box 122)
  - Moving weak patient up in bed", video cassette (Box 122)
    Cassette is super 8 magi-cartridge.
  - Occupational film ? Assembly, video cassette (Box 122)
  - Teaching shapes and color, video cassette (Box 122)
  - Wheelchair: Very weak patient from bed to chair and return", video cassette (Box 122)
  - Atypical Seminar - evaluation of HIP + operant conditioning program, audio tape (Box 123)